It so happened
that
[Music]
Gaurav had gone from Mumbai to Delhi for some work. It was
a week-long trip to Delhi.
One day, while out for a walk, he left
his pack somewhere on the way. He rushed back but found it
missing. Now he was about to find it.
What a loss! Had he
taken domestic travel insurance, this
loss would have been largely compensated.
Travel
insurance is mandatory when traveling abroad, but
we
don't take travel insurance when traveling within the country. There are several reasons for this. Firstly,
most people don't know that there is something
called domestic travel insurance.
Second, most people
think that travel insurance
only means insurance in case of an accident,
but that's not the case. Domestic travel
insurance covers medical emergencies,
loss of passport, trip cancellation, etc.
When you take an MS Word travel
plan, the amount you pay for the cover is
n't much, but it is
effective in the sense that
if unfortunately you face a medical emergency or your
luggage gets lost, you won't suffer a major blow.
Amit Chhabra is the Health & Travel Insurance Manager at policybazaar.com. It is said that to avoid
financial losses and unnecessary
medical bills during this trip, it is essential to
obtain comprehensive travel insurance coverage.
Many domestic travel
plans are available in the market. Having such a policy while traveling within the country can help you
enjoy this pleasant journey while avoiding all risks.
This
can make your trip memorable by remaining mentally free. Domestic
travel insurance covers medical
emergencies, accidents, travel-related
problems, flight delays, match cancellations, bag
encumbrances, etc.
Obtaining domestic travel insurance is
advisable for many reasons. Having this coverage provides
several benefits, such as
assistance in meeting medical expenses if the policyholder faces a travel-related health emergency while traveling to a new location. The
insurance company provides complete coverage in case of luggage theft or robbery.
You
can plan your trip efficiently without worrying about any unpleasant situation or financial loss. In case of travel-
related details or ticket cancellations, the
insurance company provides a refund. If you have
excess passport or credit card details, the cost of
making a duplicate copy of the card will be covered.  The cost is also
low. Many plans offer
assistance in case of a car or taxi breakdown, ambulance
assistance, medical evacuation, etc.
Domestic travel insurance is
advisable for several reasons. If you have this
reference, you
get help with medical expenses if the policyholder faces a travel-related emergency while traveling to a new place.
Insurance company provides full coverage in case of luggage theft or robbery. You can plan your trip for
any unforeseen situation and financial loss.
In case of travel cancellation, there is an expense incurred in making a duplicate copy of passport, credit card, etc. given to the insurance company.
In case of a car or taxi breakdown during the trip, an
assistant is available.
Medical questions related to ambulance are addressed.
Travel insurance offers a great deal. With travel
insurance, you can travel without worry. If you
are a frequent traveler, i.e., you travel continuously, then
you should definitely get this insurance. For this,
you can take a multi-trip annual domestic travel
insurance plan. For specific trips,
micro plans can also be taken on a day-wise basis.  Hey, hey,
tell me more
[praise]